Calvin Tomkins Papers
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series IV: Books, 1968-1998
  - Subseries IV.B:Merchants and Masterpieces, 1860-1989
    - Founding-Early Years, Corrections and errata memos, letters and correspondence from before and after publication, material detailing New York in the nineteenth century and the museum's founding including period book pages, newspapers, and magazines. (Box 47, Folder IV.B.4)
    - Founding-Early Years, Material detailing New York in the nineteenth century and the museum's founding including handwritten and typescript notes and source transcriptions. (Box 47, Folder IV.B.5)
    - Founding-Early Years, Includes a detailed chronology of events in 1870. (Box 47, Folder IV.B.6)
    - Cesnola, Rogers, Marquand, etc., Handwritten notes, photocopies, articles, and other material on Louis Palma di Cesnola and the museum's early years. (Box 47, Folder IV.B.7)
    - Cesnola, Rogers, Marquand, etc. (Box 47, Folder IV.B.8)
    - Cesnola, Rogers, Marquand, etc. (Box 47, Folder IV.B.9)
    - 9 & 10 - Morgan, Fry, Robinson, Kent (Box 48, Folder IV.B.10)
    - 11 & 12 - Classical & Egyptian, Includes material on the growth of the museum, on forgeries within the classical collection. (Box 48, Folder IV.B.11)
    - 11 & 12 - Classical & Egyptian, Includes typescript draft of chapter 11. (Box 48, Folder IV.B.12)
    - 12 & 13 - Riggs, Dean, Altman, Morgan, Photocopy of typescript draft. (Box 48, Folder IV.B.13)
    - 1920-1940, Amer. Wing, Includes pamphlet,The Metropolitan Museum of Art: What It Is and What It Does(New York: The Merrymount Press, 1927). (Box 48, Folder IV.B.14)
    - 1920-1940, Amer. Wing (Box 48, Folder IV.B.15)
    - 19 - Cloisters, Includes typescript draft of chapter. (Box 48, Folder IV.B.16)
    - Chapters 20 & 21 - F.H. Taylor, Includes guides to the museum from 1944 and 1947, materials on the activities of the museum during WWII and of the fate of art in Europe. (Box 48, Folder IV.B.17)
    - Chapters 20 & 21 - F.H. Taylor, 50-page unsigned typescript, and two partial photocopied typescripts, summarizing the museum's activity from the 1940s to the 1960s by a staff member of the museum (possibly Roland Redmond, president of the board of trustees of the museum during F.H. Taylor's tenure as director.) Detailed contemporary chronology of museum activities from 1940-1950. (Box 48, Folder IV.B.18)
    - 22 - Three-Museum Agreement, Materials relating to the short-lived agreement between The Museum of Modern Art, The Metropolitan Museum of Art, and the Whitney Museum of American Art to prevent overlapping collection policies and enable the sharing and transfer of artworks among the museums. 1 TLS Alfred H. Barr-CT (4/10/1968) [re: MoMA materials regarding relations between the two museums.]. (Box 49, Folder IV.B.19)
    - 22 - Three-Museum Agreement, Includes printed copy of original legal agreement, 9/15/47. (Box 49, Folder IV.B.20)
    - 23 - Hoving, Harlem, Dendur, etc. (Box 49, Folder IV.B.21)
    - 23 - Hoving, Harlem, Dendur, etc. (Box 49, Folder IV.B.22)
    - 24 - Rorimer - Aristotle (Box 49, Folder IV.B.23)
    - Financial, Photocopies of lists and charts detailing acquisition expenditures by, and gifts and bequests to, the museum from 1919 to 1961. (Box 49, Folder IV.B.24)
    - Correspondence - M.M.A., 1968-1969; Correspondence regarding factual corrections to the manuscript (including a 19-page typescript of corrections from Dorothy Shaver of the Costume Institute,) research topics, contact lists. 1 TLS Robert Moses-CT (11/22/1968). (Box 49, Folder IV.B.25)
    - Trustees and Benefactors Research Binder, Binder of alphabetically organized, tabbed, handwritten and typewritten notes and research on individual trustees and benefactors of the museum. General notes Benjamin Altman-Sam A. Lewisohn. (Box 49, Folder IV.B.26)
    - Trustees and Benefactors Research Binder, Clarence H. MacKay-Catharine Lorillard Wolfe. (Box 49, Folder IV.B.27)
    - Department Research Binder, Tabbed binder, of research and notes on individual curatorial and administrative departments of the museum arranged alphabetically by department. Includes handwritten and typewritten notes, magazine articles and book extracts. American Art, American Wing, Arms and Armor, Ancient Near East and Islamic, Contemporary Art and Costumes, Egyptian. (Box 49, Folder IV.B.28)
    - Department Research Binder, European Painting, Far Eastern Art, Greek & Roman. (Box 49, Folder IV.B.29)
    - Department Research Binder, Medieval, Musical Instruments & Concerts, Prints - Drawings, Western European Arts, Conservation, Education, The Building, Membership and Attendance, Casts, Misc. (Box 50, Folder IV.B.30)
    - Presidents, Directors, and Staff Research Binder, Binder of handwritten and typewritten research on all presidents and directors and important staff, organized chronologically by tenure. 33-page chronology of the museum Presidents. (Box 50, Folder IV.B.31)
    - Presidents, Directors, and Staff Research Binder, Directors, Staff, Current Administration. (Box 50, Folder IV.B.32)
    - Museum Pamphlets, 1934-1981; Five pamphlets and booklets including: Biography of museum co-founder George Fisk Comfort, 1934 Theodore L. Low,The Museum as a Social Instrument(American Association of Museums, 1942) Address by H.W. Kent, 1944 2 versions of the museum's charter, constitution and by-laws, 1952, 1963 History of the museum's Publications and Reproductions Program, 1981. (Box 50, Folder IV.B.33)
    - Book Photographs for 1989 Reprint, Thirty-one 8x10 black and white photographs labeled and with editorial markings. (Box 50, Folder IV.B.34)
    - Margaret A. Mazer,A History of Education at the Metropolitan Museum of Art from 1987 to 1985, Unpublished master's thesis, July 1987. (Box 50, Folder IV.B.35)
    - Linda Sipress,The History of the Centennial Celebration of The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1972; Printed typescript of the museum's activities. Folder includes correspondence regarding legal issue of Henry Holt 1989 reprint. (Box 50, Folder IV.B.36)
    - Hoving - Pro & Con - The Troubles - Harlem, Research and interview notes for the 1989 reprint including information on Thomas Hoving's tenure as director, Arthur A. Houghton's tenure as president, and the centennial celebration of 1970. Includes official program of the centennial celebrations and The Second century: The Comprehensive Architectural Plan for the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1971. (Box 51, Folder IV.B.37)
    - Juan de Pareja- Duccio, Materials on the purchase of Juan de Pareja by Diego Velzquez and the cancelled purchase of a painting by Duccio; includes interview notes with John Pope-Hennessy and others. (Box 51, Folder IV.B.38)
    - Dillon - Macomber - Luers..., Includes interview notes with Douglas Dillon on his tenure as president and material on later trustees and officials. (Box 51, Folder IV.B.39)
    - Chronology 1987-1986; Bldgs, Includes documents detailing the 1972 master expansion plan. (Box 51, Folder IV.B.40)
    - Corrections, Etc., Corrections, alterations, and rebuttals to the original edition and additions for the 1989 reprint including corrected typescripts of new chapters 26 through 29. (Box 51, Folder IV.B.41)
    - Original MS, Typescript with hand edits of new book chapters. (Box 51, Folder IV.B.42)
    - 20thCentury Dept., Materials documenting the growth of the department. (Box 51, Folder IV.B.43)
    - Asian Art (Box 51, Folder IV.B.44)
    - Met - The Scandals (), 1972-1973; Includes: "Report on Art Transactions," 1963, a public report written by a special committee of museum trustees, and other materials relating to the furor over deaccessioning, "The Euphronios Krater: A Report to the Members of the Corporation," 1974, and other materials on the debated provenance of that artwork, interview notes with Hoving and others from 1973. (Box 51, Folder IV.B.45)
    - Met - The Scandals (), 1972-1973; Includes "off the record" correspondence and documents passed to CT from Ashton Hawkins, Secretary and Counsel at the museum, in 1973, interview notes and extensive news clippings. (Box 51, Folder IV.B.46)
    - Met - The Scandals (), 1972-1973; Extensive news clippings, typescript copy of "The Euphronios Krater at the Metropolitan Museum: A Question of Provenance," article by Ashton Hawkins for The Hastings Law Journal, 1976, recapitulating the full extent of the incident 1 TLS Clement Greenberg-CT (3/12/1973) [re: appraisal of David Smith artwork acquired by the museum]. (Box 51, Folder IV.B.47)
  - Subseries IV.C:Off the Wall, 1963-1991
    In many ways,Off the Wall: Robert Rauschenberg and the Art World of Our Time(New York: Doubleday, 1980), summarizes and organizes all the writing on modern and contemporary art Tomkins had published to that moment. Scattered throughout these folders are interview notes and partial transcripts from twenty years of The New Yorker articles. The first group of files, 1-47, is in rough chronological order by topic, event and period of Rauschenberg's life. These files mostly comprise those extensive interview notes and quotations. Most of the interviews are labeled with name and date and are copies of materials found in the files of the original articles. There are scattered news clippings, magazine articles, press releases, ephemera, and other published material. Many folders have been photocopied to preserve extensive label information and cross reference notes or when labels were illegible. Folders 48-61 duplicate some of the topics and materials from the earlier folders and also include material gathered after the book's publication. Apart from the small amount of material found in folder 55 (acknowledgements, endnotes, and photograph captions,) no portions of the manuscript in draft or galley form are present. Likewise, although material exists here that was gathered for Tomkins' original Profile on Rauschenberg, "Moving Out," 2/29/1964, no manuscript of that article is present and it is likely that materials gathered for that article were thoroughly dispersed throughout these folders.
    For the original research binder assembled for the Rauschenberg Profile, see folder II.B.4; for photographs used in the book, see Series IV.E.
    - Venice Biennale 1964; World Tour - Break with Merce, 1964-1979; Includes tear sheets and manuscript of article by CT on the Biennale, "The Big Show in Venice," from Harper's Magazine(April, 1965), interview notes with Rauschenberg and others about this period, complete issue of the magazine Tropic(December 20, 1979), featuring wraparound cover by Rauschenberg and article by CT, "The Man Who Created the Most Public Work of Private Art in History.". (Box 52, Folder IV.C.1)
    - Early Life - Navy - School, etc., Typescript biographical notes interspersed with quotes. 1 TLS Janet Begneaud (Rauschenberg's sister)-CT (7/22/1963)[recollections for TNY Profile of 2/29/1964]. (Box 52, Folder IV.C.2)
    - Black Mountain - 1949..., Interview notes with various individuals including Susan Weil (Kirschenbaum). 1 ALS Josef Albers [signature illegible, on Albers' stationery]-CT (7/9/1963) [re: general reflections on student-teacher relationships]. (Box 52, Folder IV.C.3)
    - The Club - Ab-Ex Scene - "Irascible Eighteen" - Peggy Guggenheim - Pollock & de Kooning, Interview notes and materials on various aspects and personalities of the New York School, much culled from previous CT writings. (Box 52, Folder IV.C.4)
    - The Club - Ab-Ex Scene - "Irascible Eighteen" - Peggy Guggenheim - Pollock & de Kooning (Box 52, Folder IV.C.5)
    - Betty Parsons - Her Career - Barney Newman..., Interview notes and quotes from Parsons, Tony Smith, Richard Tuttle, and others. (Box 52, Folder IV.C.6)
    - Ninth Street Show (1951) - Leo Castelli - Tenth Street Scene - Barr, One page of interview quotes from Philip Johnson on Alfred H. Barr, the MoMA and Abstract Expressionism. (Box 52, Folder IV.C.7)
    - Black Mountain (1952) - Cage & Cunningham... (Box 52, Folder IV.C.8)
    - Europe - N. Africa - Cy T. (Box 52, Folder IV.C.9)
    - Fulton Street - Stable Show... (Box 52, Folder IV.C.10)
    - Dance Work - Cunningham - Paul Taylor (Box 52, Folder IV.C.11)
    - Cage - Boza mansion, etc. - His Influence, Includes original typescript program of the Pocket Theater's performance of Vexations by Erik Satie, an eighteen-hour piano composition performed by numerous musicians including John Cage and John Cale, begun September 9, 1963.. (Box 52, Folder IV.C.12)
    - Egan: The Red Show (Box 52, Folder IV.C.13)
    - Jasper Johns - Sari Dienes - Window Displays... (Box 52, Folder IV.C.14)
    - Duchamp (Box 52, Folder IV.C.15)
    - Castelli - Visit to Front Street... (Box 52, Folder IV.C.16)
    - Late Ab-Ex, etc. (Box 52, Folder IV.C.17)
    - Happenings, etc...., Includes manuscript of article on happenings by CT, apparently from the early 1960s. (Box 52, Folder IV.C.18)
    - Dante Drawings (Box 52, Folder IV.C.19)
    - Tinguely, Includes interview notes and quotations with Billy Klver, dated 1/18/1961; contemporary photocopy of manuscript by Klver, with hand edits, "The Garden Party," relating his firsthand experience of the development and execution of Homage to New York: A self-constructing & self-destroying work of art conceived and built by Jean Tinguely[MoMA Exh. #661, March 17, 1960]; extensive interview and biographical notes on Tinguely; five-page typescript of recollections by one of Tinguely's art teachers, Julia Ris; original program, with annotations, for Homage to New York. 1 TLA Pontus Hulten-CT (3/17/1961) [recollections of Tinguely] 1 empty airmail envelope, decorated and with notes by either Niki de Saint-Phalle or Jean Tinguely, (9/1/1963). (Box 52, Folder IV.C.20)
    - Bellamy, Scull & Green Gallery; Emergence of Pop; "The Store" (Box 52, Folder IV.C.21)
    - Janis Pop Show; Europe... (Box 52, Folder IV.C.22)
    - Paris Event, Tinguely Construction of Boston; Dylaby(Amsterdam), 1 ALS Sandberg-CT (n.d.) [re: on the conception of Dylaby] 1 TL K.G. (Pontus) Hulten-CT (8/2/1963) [re: Rauschenberg's experience in Stockholm]. (Box 52, Folder IV.C.23)
    - Break With Johns... (Box 52, Folder IV.C.24)
    - Tanya Grossman & ULAE (Box 52, Folder IV.C.25)
    - Alan Solomon - Jewish museum Show (March 1963) (Box 52, Folder IV.C.26)
    - Europe - Crisis 1965, 1 TLS Ileana Sonnabend-CT (8/6/1963). (Box 52, Folder IV.C.27)
    - Duchamp - Pasadena - Hopps; West Coast Art Scene (Box 52, Folder IV.C.28)
    - Judson - Dance Theater, etc., Includes original programs from the Judson Dance Theater, 1963, and from the Surplus Dance Theater, 2/10/1964, including the dance Shotput by Rauschenberg and all featuring works or performances by Robert Morris and Yvonne Rainier, among others. (Box 53, Folder IV.C.29)
    - Judson - Dance Theater, etc., Complete issue of Ballet Review 1:6 (1967), entirely dedicated to the Judson Dance Theater Annette Kuhn, ed.A Voice in the Village, Howard Moody: Twenty Years on Washington Square(New York: Judson Memorial Church, 1977). (Box 53, Folder IV.C.30)
    - First Theater Rally..., Includes program for the Rally listing participation and pieces of numerous art world notables, extensive notes of CT's observations of rehearsals and performances, programs and ephemera from other arts festivals and performances. (Box 53, Folder IV.C.31)
    - Nine Evenings - E.A.T., Includes transcriptions of numerous Nine Evenings documents. (Box 53, Folder IV.C.32)
    - E.A.T. (Post - Nine Evenings), Includes photocopy of 36-page typescript, "Rainforest" by Billy Klver, a history of E.A.T., dated 1/30/1970, E.A.T. ephemera, photocopies of correspondence between E.A.T. and Pepsi-Cola (Japan) regarding the Pepsi-Cola pavilion at Expo '70 in Osaka, Japan. (Box 53, Folder IV.C.33)
    - Greenberg - Post-Painterly Abstraction (Box 53, Folder IV.C.34)
    - "Primary Structures" - Minimal - Op (Responsive Eye at MoMA) (Box 53, Folder IV.C.35)
    - The Scene - Circa 1967 (Box 53, Folder IV.C.36)
    - Warhol, Includes undated 20-page photocopied typescript, "The Shooting of Andy Warhol (A Historical Poem in the Manner of William McGonagall)," authored by "the eel" and inscribed to CT. (Box 53, Folder IV.C.37)
    - Dude Period - Soundings... (Box 53, Folder IV.C.38)
    - "Henry's Show" at Met - Oldenburg, Lichtenstein Retrospectives (Box 53, Folder IV.C.39)
    - Castelli - New Developments - SoHo - Satellites (Box 53, Folder IV.C.40)
    - Stoned Moon - Bob Peterson - Carnal Clocks, Includes copy of previous folder with label but no contents. (Box 53, Folder IV.C.41)
    - Politics - Angry Art... (Box 53, Folder IV.C.42)
    - Currents... (Box 53, Folder IV.C.43)
    - Cardboards - "Change" - Captiva (Box 53, Folder IV.C.44)
    - Israel - India... (Box 53, Folder IV.C.45)
    - Scull Auction - "Blue Poles" $2 Million... (Box 53, Folder IV.C.46)
    - Smithsonian Retrospective, Includes interview notes with Walter Hopps and Kynaston McShine on the retrospective Robert Rauschenberg[MoMA Exh. #1170, March 25-May 17, 1977]. (Box 53, Folder IV.C.47)
    - Allan Kaprow - Happenings, Programs and ephemera of happenings and events by Kaprow. (Box 53, Folder IV.C.48)
    - Happenings, etc. (Box 53, Folder IV.C.49)
    - Nine Evenings - E.A.T., Photocopies of writings and original documents of the event. (Box 54, Folder IV.C.50)
    - Nine Evenings - E.A.T., 1969; Issue of E.A.T. Clippings 1:1 (April 1960-July 1969). (Box 54, Folder IV.C.51)
    - R.O.C.I., 1987-1991; Includes two drafts of brochure text by CT for the Rauschenberg Overseas Cultural Interchange. (Box 54, Folder IV.C.52)
    - Abstract Expressionists (Box 54, Folder IV.C.53)
    - Abstract Expressionists, Issue of Arts Magazine 50:7 (March 1976) devoted entirely to Arshille Gorky. (Box 54, Folder IV.C.54)
    - Manuscript Materials, Endnotes for book and copy of acknowledgement text, typescript with hand edits of photograph captions, list of individuals to whom complimentary copies of the book were sent. (Box 54, Folder IV.C.55)
    - Sixties, General (Box 54, Folder IV.C.56)
    - Book Release Party Materials, Manuscript and typescript list of invitees, invitation for party hosted by Leo Castelli. (Box 54, Folder IV.C.57)
    - Pre-War - Wartime - Europeans - Surrealism (Box 54, Folder IV.C.58)
    - Rauschenberg - 1960s & 1970s, Includes chapter descriptions and cover letter for book proposal by CT on American art since 1945, 3/13/1976. (Box 54, Folder IV.C.59)
    - MoMA, 1968-1977; Press releases, news clippings, and mailings from the museum, many concerning John B. Hightower and the labor unrest of the period. (Box 54, Folder IV.C.60)
    - Photos - RR Book, Bills, costs and documentation of book photography. (Box 54, Folder IV.C.61)
  - Subseries IV.D:Duchamp: A Biography, 1953-1998
    Tomkins' biography of Duchamp, titled Duchamp: A Biography(New York: Henry Holt, 1996) required more historical research than any of his previous books. There are large quantities of photocopies, hand transcriptions, and translations of significant original documents (such as correspondence and personal journals) pertaining to Duchamp and his social circle. Much of this archival material was viewed in collections at the Beinecke Library of Yale University, the Archives of American Art, and the Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center at the University of Texas at Austin. The first group of folders, 1-29, is arranged in chronological order by decade, and corresponds to eventual book chapters. Groups of folders are dedicated to published and unpublished interview transcripts with Duchamp, reader responses, photographs and reproduction rights and permissions, post-mortem critical evaluations of Duchamp, and extensive correspondence. Much of the correspondence is with Duchamp's surviving family: his stepdaughter Jacqueline Matisse Monnier and his widow, Alexina "Teeny" Duchamp. Teeny Duchamp was herself able to review Tomkins' book in manuscript form before her death in 1995. There is also extensive correspondence with other Duchamp scholars, particularly Francis Naumann. Finally, there are five bound volumes of photocopies from two collections at the Beinecke Library. They seem to be the complete extent of correspondence between Duchamp, Katherine Dreier, and Katharine Kuh, taken from those women's personal papers. The volumes are in folders IV.D.68-69.
    Of particular note in these files are folders IV.D.29 and IV.D.63 that contain complete transcripts of Tomkins' 1964 interviews with Duchamp. Also, see folder I.64 for a copy of a 1997 letter written by Tomkins in which he describes his initial meeting with Duchamp and his ensuing personal interest and relationship with the artist.
    - Blainville - Family - Childhood (Box 55, Folder IV.D.1)
    - Loose Materials, These materials were found between folders. Spiral notebook of research contacts and biographical notes, list of corrections to book. (Box 55, Folder IV.D.2)
    - 1904-1914 (Box 55, Folder IV.D.3)
    - 1904-1914 (Box 55, Folder IV.D.4)
    - 1904-1914, Includes photocopied typescript, Thomas Edward Lippy, Jr., "The Influence of Max Steiner's Philosophy on the Art and Thought of Marcel Duchamp," 5/3/1987. (Box 55, Folder IV.D.5)
    - 1904-1914 (Box 55, Folder IV.D.6)
    - Ettie Stettheimer - Journals & Letters (Box 55, Folder IV.D.7)
    - Hubachek - Mary Reynolds File (Box 55, Folder IV.D.8)
    - Duchamp - Alice Roullier (Box 55, Folder IV.D.9)
    - M.D. & Chess (Box 55, Folder IV.D.10)
    - Maria Martins, 1998; Bound photocopy of catalogue Maria: The Surrealist Sculpture of Maria Martins(New York: Andr Emmerich gallery, 3/19-4/18/1998). (Box 55, Folder IV.D.11)
    - Maria Martins, Includes interview notes and quotations with Maria Martins' daughter, Nora Martins Lobo, 1989-90. (Box 56, Folder IV.D.12)
    - Maria Martins, Restricted material, please see Museum Archivist. (Box 56, Folder IV.D.13)
    - New York 1915-1918 Arensbergs - Argentina, Includes detailed, day-by-day chronologies of H.P. Roche and Beatrice Wood. (Box 56, Folder IV.D.14)
    - New York 1915-1918 Arensbergs - Argentina (Box 56, Folder IV.D.15)
    - New York 1915-1918 Arensbergs - Argentina (Box 56, Folder IV.D.16)
    - 1920s (Box 56, Folder IV.D.17)
    - 1930s (Box 56, Folder IV.D.18)
    - 1940s (Box 56, Folder IV.D.19)
    - 1940s (Box 56, Folder IV.D.20)
    - 1940s (Box 57, Folder IV.D.21)
    - 1950s (Box 57, Folder IV.D.22)
    - 1950s, Includes photocopy of article by CT on Duchamp from Newsweek, 11/7/1957, 8-page typescript of recollections of Marcel and Teeny Duchamp in New York by Jacqueline Monnier. (Box 57, Folder IV.D.23)
    - 1960s (Box 57, Folder IV.D.24)
    - 1960s, Includes photocopied transcript of the Art of Assemblage symposium, held at MoMA 10/19/1961, with Rauschenberg and Duchamp among the panel members. (Box 57, Folder IV.D.25)
    - Large Glass (Box 57, Folder IV.D.26)
    - M.D. - Interviews (1960s), Photocopies of published and unpublished interviews with Duchamp by other authors. (Box 57, Folder IV.D.27)
    - M.D. - Interviews (1960s) (Box 57, Folder IV.D.28)
    - M.D. - Interviews (1960s), 1964-1965; Two copies of 44-page typescript transcript of CT's interview with Duchamp on 3/23 and 3/26/1964 and notes on later, unrecorded, interviews. (Box 57, Folder IV.D.29)
    - Etant donns, Includes photocopies of correspondence between The Philadelphia Museum of Art and Teeny Duchamp regarding the museum's acquisition of Etant donns. (Box 58, Folder IV.D.30)
    - Duchamp Miscellaneous, Numerous typescript pages of extracts and quotations from CT's interviews with Duchamp, extensive handwritten notes on Duchamp's early life. (Box 58, Folder IV.D.31)
    - Duchamp Miscellaneous, Includes various chronologies of Duchamp's life, list of addresses from throughout his life, and other research materials. (Box 58, Folder IV.D.32)